farnood.me foroudi@gmail.com (+98) 936 476 5685

Education

Shomal UniversityBS Software Engineering

Skills

Product Design

Product Business Strategy
Product Life Cycle Process

Creative Storytelling

Product Road Map

Competitive Analysis

Data Analysis

Interaction Design

Rapid Prototyping

Typography

Usability Evaluation

User Research

Visual Design

Wireframing

Tools

Sketch

Adobe Creative Suite

Principle

Flinto

Origami

Zeplin Abstract

Zeroheight

InVision

MindNode

Aha!

Jira

Programming

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Achievements

Iran Web and Mobile Awards

Dunro (twice)

Fidilio

Seebstore

UX Tehran Awards

Digikala: Application of the Year

Speaks

Cycle Meets 2019

Product Design for Iranian People: Stories from Dunro

About

I'm a product designer from Tehran, Iran. I have 5 years experience designing and crafting digital products in Iran. I've been helping companies in different sizes defining their product strategy, design approach and solutions to their users. I have a solid background in interface design, user experience design and user research.

Work Experience

Alibaba Travels / Product Manager - Mobile Application

FEB 2019 - PRESENT, TEHRAN

• I've built a product development process to manage the complete existing app redesign alongside the expanding of product coverage and development of new mobile-only features with speed and future scalability in mind • I'm directly working with 2 UX designer in my team to deliver a brand new design based on user researches, usability testing and direct contact with customers • I'm working with the marketing team to utilize the marketing automation tool inside the apps • I'm helping the company to recruit, shape and build the product design team to form a decentralized chapter of product designers • I'm initiating the Alibaba's Design Language System across the whole company.

Kian Capital Management / Product Designer

FEB 2018 - FEB 2019, TEHRAN

My main responsibility was to create and shape a new digital banking/personal finance management experience in Iran • I was responsible for taking the digital banking from ideation to production. This included vision setting, conducting research, designing solutions, creating high-fidelity visuals, prototyping new ideas, presenting work to our cross-functional teams, and overseeing implementation • I designed a complex KYC and On-Boarding process to tackle the problems of bank account oppening procedure in Iran • I successfully designed a robust design structure for Kian's future product expansion • I initated and led the first version of Kian Design Language System in collaboration with other product designers in my team.

Dunro / Product Designer

SEP 2015 - FEB 2018, TEHRAN

During my time at Dunro, I crafted and developed the product's vision to evolve iBartar (former name of Dunro) from a simple local business search engine to a complete location-based city guide application with social contribution and network platform • I was in charge of ideation and production of core business values like: Targeted Advertisement Platform, Rate and Review System, Dunro's Gamification Platform, new Adding Locations Flow, Social Feed and the Superusers Program • The DAU and user retention rates successfully increased by more than 40% in 6 month after introducing our social and gamification features • Our app users boosted from 100K to 500K in 1 year. We managed to raise a \$15M investment that year by Aftab Group • During my time, Dunro won the Iran Web and Mobile Awards, twice, for being the best application in Travel and Lifestyle segments.

Digikala / UI-UX Designer

JUN 2015 - SEP 2015, TEHRAN

Digikala is the most popular and biggest e-commerce website in MENA region. I joined Digikala as a Senior UI/UX designer, my main responsibility was to redesign the whole mobile application experience. • In 3 month I successfully redesigned the application and followed development team to deliver the product • My designs was based on user research and tests conducted by by our research team and myself • Digikala won the Iran UX Award that year.

Seeb Mobile Technologies / Co-Founder, UI-UX Designer

OCT 2013 - MAY 2015, TEHRAN

I founded Seeb as a mobile solutions agency to offer mobile application development, consultancy and product design to Iranian companies • We successfully designed and developed mobile apps by contract for great companies in Iran like NetBarg (Coupon Deals), Parsian Bank (Mobile Bank App), Buyex (Online Apparel Shop), Fidilio (Popular Restaurant Review App) • We also launched a series of applications for our company like Tehran Air (Air Quality Check), SeebStore (A payment solution for Iranian users with no access to visa/master), Golabi (An iOS trivia game) • I was a multidisciplinary individual working mainly on product design and project management.

Mapna Group / UI-UX Designer

OCT 2012 - SEP 2014, TEHRAN

I started off my professional career with Mapna Group, working on internal enterprise portals over Microsoft SharePoint foundation. During my time at Mapna I successfully turned the majority of traditional paperwork workflows into fully automated workflows in collaboration with the Systems and Quality department engineers. I was also in charge of designing and developing the company's website which I successfully designed and developed and launched it on .NET platform.